[音乐]
well now that we've got a really good
好吧，现在我们已经非常欣赏这些作品了
appreciation for the pieces of the router the input ports the output ports and
路由输入端口、输出端口和我们将要使用的交换结构
深入研究数据包调度和缓冲区管理的主题以及
the switching fabric we're going to dive down deep into the topics of packet
我们已经看到这些对于 Internet 的尽力服务模型的重要性
scheduling and buffer management and we've seen how important these are with the Internet's
数据包丢失和数据包延迟对必须发生的事情产生了深远的影响
best effort service model packet loss and packet delay have had a profound effect
传输层和应用层 所以现在我们要深入 研究数据包调度和缓冲区管理的主题和
on what has to happen the transport layers and the application layers so now
we're going to dive down deep into the topics of packet scheduling and buffer
我们将看看如何使用它们来控制和缓解数据包
management and we'll take a look at how those can be used to control
丢失和数据包延迟让我们首先看一下输入
and also mitigate packet loss and packet delay well let's get started by first
端口排队记住我们之前看到的输入端口排队可以
taking a look at input port queuing remember that we saw earlier that input
当路由器交换结构小于其组合速率时发生
port queuing can happen when the routers switching fabric is less than the combined
在这种情况下，传入链接在单位时间内可以到达更多的数据包，然后
rates of its incoming links in this case more packets can arrive in a
交换结构可能从结构的输入端移动到
unit time then the switching fabric can possibly move from the input side of
输出端等会在输入端出现排队现象
the fabric to the output side and so queuing can occur on the input
交换结构的输入端所独有的就是所谓的头
side a queuing phenomena that's unique to the input side of the switching fabric
当数据包在
is what's known as head of the line blocking or hol end of the
如果一个包只有一个包，不同的输入端口想要去同一个输出端口
line blocking occurs when packets at different input ports want to go to the
same output port if only one pack at a
时间可以从一个输入转移到一个给定的输出端口，如果有 K
time can be transferred from an input to
a given output port and if there are K
想要到达相同输出端口的数据包，然后 K 减 1
packets that want to go to the same
output port then K minus 1 of those
数据包将不得不在交换机的输入端等待，如果数据包
packets are going to have to wait on the
input side of the switch and if packets
必须等待他们也可以在他们的输入队列中阻止他们后面的数据包
have to wait they can also block the
packets behind them in their input queue
从前进，这就是所谓的线头阻塞采取
from moving forward and this is what's
known as head of the line blocking take
看看这里的例子，其中数据包的颜色对应于
a look at this example here where the
colors of the packets correspond to the
在这个例子中它们注定要到达的输出端口说在时间 T 我们看到
output port to which they're destined in
this example say at time T we see the
顶部和底部输入端口有一个红色数据包，目的地为上部输出端口
top and bottom input ports have a red
packet destined to the upper output port
在一个时钟甲板上，上面的红包从输入传输到
in one clock deck the upper red packet
is transferred from the input to the
开关的输出端中间的蓝色数据包也可以
output side of the switch the blue
packet in the middle it's also able to
将底部的红色数据包从其输入端口移动到其输出端口
move from its input port to its output
port the red packet at the bottom
但是被锁定无法移动到读取输出
however is
locked from moving to the read output
端口，因为顶部的数据包已经传输到那里，所以
port since the packet at the top was
already transferred there and so the
这个较低的红包后面的绿包经历了排队
green packet behind this lower red
packet experiences head of the line
阻塞让我们现在专注于输出端口侧，因为这确实是
blocking let's now focus on the output
port side since this is really where the
行动是，让我们首先看看为什么需要缓冲
action is and let's start by seeing why
buffering is needed in the first place
在这个输出端口，我们有一个传输速率为每秒比特的链接
at this output port we have a link with
transmission rate of our bits per second
假设我们有一个能够提供结束时间的非阻塞开关
and let's say we have a non-blocking
switch capable of delivering end times
我们每秒传输到输出端口的位现在我们可以看到为什么会发生缓冲位
our bits per second to the output port
now we can see why buffering occurs bits
可以以一定的速率到达结束时间，但是位只能被排出或
can be arriving at a rate of end times
are but bits can only be drained or
每当到达率超过
transmitted out at a rate of are
whenever the arrival rate exceeds the
缓冲区将填充的出发率，并且由于缓冲区是有限的，因此可能不会
departure rate the buffer will fill and
since buffers are finite there may not
有足够的缓冲空间来存储所有需要缓冲的数据包和
be enough buffer space to store all of
the packets that need buffering and
数据包将不得不被丢弃，因为没有足够的内存来容纳所有
packets will have to be dropped there
simply isn't enough memory to hold all
需要缓冲的数据包在输出端口的位置是
of the packets that need buffering so
right here at the output port is where
发生拥塞性数据包丢失，您知道可能很想说它是
congestive packet loss occurs and you
know it may be tempting to say well it's
确实是交换机结构故障，它以 5 倍的速率传送数据包太快
really the switch fabrics fault it's
delivering packets too fast at a rate of
结束时间是链路只能以 R 速率消耗的时间，因此我们应该减慢
end times are when the link can only
drain at rate R so we should slow the
面料下降，但这并不是问题的真正原因是它回想一下
fabric down but that's not really the
cause of the problem is it think back to
我们之前对拥塞控制原理的讨论 导致拥塞的真正原因
our earlier discussion of principles of
congestion control the real cause of the
问题拥塞是边缘传输层发送方太多
problem congestion is that there are too
many transport layer senders at the edge
网络发送太多数据包太快数据包的路径交叉
of the network sending too many packets
too fast packets whose paths cross at
这个拥塞的输出端口在缓冲和拥塞面前有一个
this congested output port in the face
of buffering and congestion there are a
如果有的话，首先需要在输出端口做出几个决定
couple of decisions that'll need to be
made at the output port first if there's
没有足够的空间容纳所有到达的数据包，将需要数据包丢弃策略
not enough room for all arriving packets
a packet drop policy will be needed to
确定哪些数据包将被丢弃，以及是否有多个数据包
determine which packets are going to be
dropped and if there are multiple
缓冲区中的数据包等待传输 数据包调度
packets in the buffer awaiting
transmission a packet scheduling
在众多可爱的包中选择哪些包是需要纪律的
discipline will be needed to choose
which packets among the many cute
接下来将传输数据包，我们将查看丢弃和调度
packets will be transmitted next we'll
look at both drop and scheduling
一秒钟的政策现在有很多非常重要的想法
policies in just a second now there are
a lot of really important idea
我们刚刚在这张幻灯片上讨论过，所以请确保你已经掌握了所有内容
that we just talked about here on this
slide so make sure you've got it all
鉴于缓冲是如此之大，您可能会认为这真的很重要
it's really important well you might be
thinking given buffering is such a big
关心路由器应该有多少缓冲，更重要的是你
concern how much buffering should a
router have and more to the point you
也可能在思考，嘿，投资不应该是个好主意吗？
might also be thinking well hey
shouldn't it be a good idea to invest in
大量缓冲和大量缓冲会减少丢包率
a lot of buffering with a lot of
buffering there'd be less packet loss
因为会有更多的缓冲区来观察突发性和数据包流
since there'll be more buffers to
observe the burstiness and packet flows
拥有更多缓冲一定是一件好事，它可能会让您感到惊讶
having more buffering must be a good
thing right well it might surprise you
即使在 50 年后，缓冲多少才是合适的问题
that even after 50 years the question of
how much buffering is the right amount
缓冲仍然是一个未解决的问题，有一些
of buffering is still pretty much an
unresolved issue there are some
建议您可以查看 RFC 3439 并找到一个经验法则
recommendations you could take a look at
RFC 3439 and find a rule of thumb that
说缓冲量应该等于典型的 RTT 说几百
says the amount of buffering should
equal a typical RTT say a couple hundred
毫秒倍的输出链接容量最近也有更多
milliseconds times the output link
capacity there's also been more a recent
假设传输层发送者通常是
theoretical research that assumes that
transport layer senders are generally
彼此独立，建议将 RFC 34:39 的数量分开
independent of each other and recommends
dividing the RFC 34:39 amount of
通过 n 的平方根进行缓冲，其中 n 是穿过
buffering by the square root of n where
n is the number of flows crossing the
链接，这减少了很多缓冲，虽然你可能有感觉
link and that's a lot less buffering and
while you might have the sense that
大缓冲区通常会导致更少的损失，你可能是对的
large buffers will generally result in
less loss and you could be right
大缓冲区确实有缺点 大缓冲区意味着更大的延迟和更大的 RT  的大延迟对游戏玩家和交互式电话会议用户不利
large buffers do have a downside large
buffers mean larger delays and larger RT
大缓冲区确实有缺点 大缓冲区意味着更大的延迟和更大的 RT  的大延迟对游戏玩家和交互式电话会议用户不利
T's large delays are bad for gamers and
for interactive teleconferencing users
几十毫秒确实很重要，但可能更重要
where tens of milliseconds really do
matter but maybe even more importantly
较大的 RTT 延迟意味着 TCP 发送方的检测速度较慢，因此
large RTT delays mean that TCP senders
will be slower to detect and therefore
对拥塞做出反应，您可能还记得，当我们研究基于延迟的
react to congestion you might recall
that when we studied delay based
拥塞控制我们遇到了说我们要保持
congestion control we encountered the
saying that we want to keep the
瓶颈链接刚好足以让链接保持忙碌，但没有更满，但那是
bottleneck link just full enough to keep
the link busy but no fuller but that was
从发送主机的角度考虑
from the perspective of the sending
hosts when we think about the amount of
缓冲我们确实希望缓冲吸收短期统计数据 包到达率的波动并保持链路繁忙但不如此
buffering we really do want buffers to
absorb short term statistical
缓冲我们确实希望缓冲吸收短期统计数据 包到达率的波动并保持链路繁忙但不如此
fluctuation in packet arrival rates and
to keep the link busy but not to have so
大量缓冲使拥塞控制动作时间变得缓慢和缓慢
much buffering that congestion control
action times become slow and sluggish
很好的缓冲有点像盐和烹饪你必须找到合适的
well buffering sort of like salt and
cooking you've got to find the right
数量恰到好处
amount
just the right amount makes things
更好，但太多真的会毁了事情谁会想到
better but too much can really ruin
things well who would have thought that
输出端口的缓冲和排队实际上可能如此复杂
buffering and queuing at an output port
could actually be so complicated and so
微妙，你可能会问自己为什么会这样，这真的是因为它在这里
subtle and you may ask yourself why is
that and it's really because it's here
在输出端口缓冲区，潜在的数千个全局行为
at an output port buffer that the global
behavior of potentially thousands of
全球活跃的发件人正在汇聚，因为他们的流量都经过
active senders worldwide are converging
as their flows all pass through the
单一输出链接我们看到全球互联网规模的融合
single output link we see the
convergence of global internet scale
在互联网深处的这个位置的行为非常酷
behavior at this one location deeply
inside the internet that's pretty cool
好吧，我们接下来将继续讨论缓冲区管理机制和
well we're next going to move on to the
mechanisms for buffer management and
数据包调度，会发现考虑输出端口很有用
packet scheduling and will find it
useful to think of an output port
抽象地作为一个队列，如图所示当然我们都熟悉排队
abstractly as a queue as shown here of
course we're all familiar with queuing
我们日常生活中的系统 银行 巴士站 食品店
systems in our daily lives banks at
buses at bus stops at food stores at
地铁和许多其他地方想想你今天去过多少个立方体
metros and many other places think about
how many cubes you've been in today
数据包到达他们等待服务的队列，他们最终
packets arrive to the queue they wait
for service and they're eventually
选择为服务接收服务，然后离开队列链路层
selected for service receive service and
then leave the queue the link layer
当数据包比特通过网络传输时充当服务器
functions as the server when a packets
bits are being transmitted over the
如果到达的数据包出现在服务中的数据包的传出链路
outgoing link that packets in service if
an arriving packet emerges from the
交换结构以发现数据包没有可用的缓冲区空间
switching fabric to find there's no free
buffer space either that packets going
被丢弃，这被称为尾部丢弃或已经排队的数据包可能
to be dropped and that's known as tail
drop or an already queued packet could
从缓冲区中移除并放下，为这个新来的人腾出空间
be removed from the buffer and dropped
to make room for this newly arriving
数据包根据某种优先级机制说，例如那里
packet say according to some kind of
priority mechanism for example there
可能是丢弃低优先级数据包的策略，比如携带最终用户 TCP
might be a policy to drop low priority
packets say carrying end-user TCP
流量而不是高优先级数据包说承载网络管理
traffic rather than high priority
packets say carrying Network management
在 ISP 的控制数据包中，正如我们在学习网络时也学到的
in control packets for the ISP as we
also learned when we studied Network
辅助拥塞控制缓冲的数据包也可以标记为
assisted congestion control a buffered
packet may also be marked with a
拥塞指示表明链路正在变得拥塞我们了解到
congestion indication to signal that the
link is becoming congested we learned
早些时候，对于互联网的明显拥塞
earlier that for the
internet's explicit congestion
通知 ecn 机制到服务字段的 IP 头类型中的位是
notification ecn mechanism to bits in
the IP header type of service field are
用于 ecn 标记的将在接下来的 IP 数据报头中看到这些位
used for ecn marking will see these bits
in the IP datagram header in the next
我们研究 ipv4 时的部分，但它在输出端口和拥塞的地方
section when we study ipv4 but it's here
at the output ports and where congestion
发生这些位将被设置我们现在可以查看几个数据包
occurs that these bits are going to be
set we can now look at several packet
在先到先得的原则下在实践中使用的调度规则
scheduling disciplines that are used in
practice under first come first serve
调度数据包只是按照它们到达的顺序传输
scheduling packets are transmitted
simply in the order in which they arrive
到输出端口我们都熟悉先到先服务排队我是
to the output port we're all familiar
with first-come first-serve queuing I'm
猜测这是人们最常做的事情，我们都排在队伍的后面，
guessing it's what people do the most we
all join the back of the queue and
从队列的前面为客户提供服务
customers are served from the front of
the queue
与数据包相同的事情我们都熟悉优先队列
same thing with packets
we're all familiar with priority queues
你可以用航空公司的白金钻石金银或青铜级
you get that with Airlines platinum
diamond gold silver or bronze class of
服务，它们听起来都很花哨，很棒，但您绝对愿意
service they all sound pretty fancy and
great but you definitely rather be
白金比青铜我想大家大概都有一个直观的认识
platinum than bronze and I think we all
probably have an intuitive understanding
优先学科如何工作一直处于较低优先级
of how priority disciplines work having
been in the lower priority class of
服务并看到较晚到达的优先级较高的人
service and seeing later arriving people
in higher priority classes getting
服务在我们之前优先调度到达的数据包
service before us under priority
scheduling packets arriving at the
输出链路在到达队列时按优先级分类，如图所示
output link are classified into priority
classes on arrival at the queue as shown
在这里，我们有一个高优先级的红色流量和一个较低的优先级
here where we have a high priority red
class of traffic and a lower priority
绿色流量优先排队规则将传输一个
green class of traffic the priority
queueing discipline will transmit a
来自具有非空队列的最高优先级类的数据包
packet from the highest priority class
that has a non-empty queue that is has
等待传输的数据包在同一个数据包中的选择
packets waiting for transmission the
choice among packets in that same
优先级通常以先到先得的方式完成
priority class is typically done in a
first-come first-serve manner this
动画显示从顶部进入服务的数据包根据
animation shows packets arriving from
the top entering service according to a
优先规则，然后在这个例子中离开队列数据包一到达
priority discipline and then leaving the
queue in this example packet one arrives
发现队列为空并进入服务，而数据包一在服务数据包中
finds the queue empty and enters service
while packet one is in service packet
当数据包 1 完成时，数据包 2 和数据包 3 都到达了
two and three arrived when packet one
finishes both packets two and three are
缓冲但数据包 3 被选择传输，即使它到达
buffered but packet three is chosen for
transmission even though it arrived
在第二个数据包之后，因为它比第二个数据包具有更高的优先级，依此类推
after packet two since it has higher
priority than back at two and so on
好吧，我们现在已经了解了优先级排队机制，但您可能
well we've now learned about the
priority queuing mechanism but you may still be wondering what is it that defines
仍然想知道是什么定义了第一个优先级
放置如何确定进入优先级 1 或优先级的内容
a priority class in the first place how is it determined what goes into
2 例如，这实际上是由网络运营商决定的
priority class 1 or priority class 2 for example and this is actually determined
ISP ISP 可能会决定网络管理流量的真正
by the network operator by the ISP the ISP may decide that well network
重要的是它是最高优先级的 ip 语音获得更高的优先级
management traffic's really important it's the highest priority class voice-over-ip gets higher priority than
比电子邮件等等，您可以通过查看传输层记住这一点
email and so on and you remember
than email and so on and you remember
比电子邮件等等，您可以通过查看传输层记住这一点
that by looking at the transport layer port numbers one can determine what type
端口号可以确定该数据携带的流量类型
of traffic is being carried by that data
现在绘制流量类型是确定优先级的一种方式
graph now traffic type is one way in
which priorities could be determined
另一种方式可能是基于源地址甚至目标地址，所以
another way might be on the basis of
source or even destination addresses so
这是将流量分类为优先级的另一种可能方法，想象一下
here's another possible way to classify
traffic into priority classes imagine
一家公司愿意向互联网服务提供商付款以提供其
that a company is willing to pay an
internet service provider to give its
数据包更好的服务数据包不太可能被丢弃它的数据包受到影响
packets better service packets are less
likely to be dropped its packets suffer
如果它是一家搜索公司，那么它的搜索结果就会到达用户手中，从而减少延迟
less delay as a result if it's a search
company its search results get to users
如果是 IP 语音，则速度更快；如果是流媒体，则语音响应更快
faster if it's voice over IP the voice
is more responsive if it's streaming
视频 旋转饭菜少了 我们有调度机制
video there's less spinning meals well
we've got the scheduling mechanisms to
无论公司是否能够支付这种更好的服务，都这样做
do that whether or not a company is able
to pay for that kind of better service
实际上让我们进入了所谓的网络中立性话题
actually gets us into the topic of
what's known as network neutrality we're
马上就会讲到，但首先让我们看几个
going to cover that in just a second but
first let's wrap up by looking at a few
更多的调度规则，所以我们已经看到了先到先服务和优先级
more scheduling disciplines so we've
seen first-come first-serve and priority
循环调度下的调度包被分配给类
scheduling under round-robin scheduling
packets are assigned to classes as with
然而，优先级调度而不是严格的服务优先级
priority scheduling however rather than
there being a strict service priority
在班级之间，循环调度程序在班级之间交替服务
among classes a round-robin scheduler
alternates service among classes for
例如，循环调度程序将从类 1 中选择一个数据包，然后是
example a round-robin scheduler would
choose a packet from class 1 followed by
来自第 2 类的数据包后跟来自第 3 类的数据包，依此类推，如果
a packet from class 2 followed by a
packet from class 3 and so on and if
没有给定类的数据包调度程序移动到下一个类
there's no packet of a given class the
scheduler moves on to the next class in
时间表是循环的一般形式
the schedule
a generalized form of round-robin
在路由器和实践中广泛实施的排队被称为
queuing that's been widely implemented
in routers and practice is known as
加权公平排队 wfq 轻优先级和循环调度到达
weighted fair queuing wfq light priority
and round-robin scheduling arriving
数据包被分类并在适当的每类等待区排队，我们
packets are classified and queued in the
appropriate per class waiting area we
在这里看到红色、绿色和蓝色的数据包等待它们的服务加权
see here red green and blue packets
waiting for their service a weighted
公平排队调度程序首先以类似循环的方式调度课程
fair queuing scheduler schedules classes
in a round-robin like manner first
服务第 1 类，然后服务第 2 类，然后服务第 3 类，然后假设
serving class 1 then serving class 2
then serving class 3 and then assuming
只有三个类重复服务模式加权公平
there are just three classes repeating
that service pattern weighted fair
排队与循环的不同之处在于每个班级都可以收到一个
queuing differs from round-robin  that each class can receive a
in that each class can receive a
在任何时间间隔内提供不同数量的服务，这是它的工作原理 想情况下，每一类数据包我都有一个重量 W sub 我假设所有的
different amount of service in any interval of time and here's how it works
ideally each class of packets I has a
在任何时间间隔内提供不同数量的服务，这是它的工作原理 想情况下，每一类数据包我都有一个重量 W sub 我假设所有的
weight W sub I let's assume that all of
权重 WJ 的总和说在任何期间加权公平排队下总和为 1
the weights the sum of W J say sum up to
1 under weighted fair queuing during any
有 I 类数据包要发送 I 类的时间间隔
interval of time during which there are
class I packets to send class I will
然后保证收到服务 W sub I 的一小部分，这意味着如果
then be guaranteed to receive a fraction
of service W sub I that means if the
链接的速率为 R，那么每个服务类别都将获得保证的最小值
link has a rate R then each class of
service will get a guaranteed minimum
带宽量 W sub I 乘以 R，因此我们可以看到加权公平排队
amount of bandwidth W sub I times R and
so we can see how weighted fair queuing
允许在每个类上保证某种类型的带宽
allows some type of a bandwidth
guaranteed to be made on a per class
基础网络中立性是我们技术感兴趣的领域
basis network neutrality is an area
where our technical interests in
计算机网络与社会政治和经济相交
computer networking intersect with
social political and economic
考虑因素 我们已经看到了共享资源的机制，但是
considerations well we've already seen
the mechanisms for sharing resources but
社会政治和经济方面的考虑如何？
what about the social political and
economic considerations about how those
资源共享让我们来看看网络中立是关于法律和
resources are shared let's take a look
network neutrality is about the laws and
管理 Internet 服务提供商如何使用流量的策略
policies that govern how an Internet
service provider can use the traffic
我们刚刚了解的数据包调度的控制机制
control mechanisms that we've just
learned about packet scheduling in
特别是控制网络流量，所以有哪些问题
particular to control network traffic so
what are some of the questions that
网络中立性很好地解决了它与许多不同的事情有关 于言论自由，例如大炮 Espie 拒绝携带某些类型的
network neutrality addresses well it's
about a number of different things it's
网络中立性很好地解决了它与许多不同的事情有关 于言论自由，例如大炮 Espie 拒绝携带某些类型的
about free speech for example cannon
Espie refused to carry some types of
交通，例如某些类型的新闻或政治观点，它也是
traffic for example certain types of
news or political opinion it's also
例如，关于鼓励创新和关于鼓励竞争必须
about encouraging innovation and about
encouraging competition for example must
ISP 为所有大大小小的公司提供与您一样的流量待遇
an isp give all companies big and small
equal treatment of their traffic as you
可能知道不同的国家一直在采取不同的立场
probably know different countries have
been adopting different stances with
关于这些问题，我们将看看发生了什么
respect to these questions we're going
to take a look at what's happening in
美国，因为这是有据可查的，并且一直在发挥作用
the united states since this is well
documented and has all been playing out
相当公开地，我们的教科书有一些关于网络的有趣参考
pretty publicly our textbooks got some
interesting references about net
您可能想在 2015 年看看的全球中立性
neutrality worldwide that you might want
to take a look at in 2015 the United
各州联邦通信委员会关于保护和促进
States Federal Communications Commission
order on protecting and promoting an
开放互联网定义了与网络相关的三个明确的明确规则
open Internet defined three clear bright
line rules associated with network
中立让我们来看看他们是什么第一条明线规则是
neutrality let's take a look at what
they are the first bright line rule is
没有阻塞，这就是它所说的，它说 isp 引用 unquote 不应
no blocking and here's what it says it
says that an isp quote unquote shall not
阻止合法的内容应用服务或无害设备主体
block lawful content applications
services or non-harmful devices subject
引用中的合理网络管理现在有很多东西
to reasonable network management in
quote now there's a lot packed in there
合法和应用程序服务和设备这个词很好这个规则
the word lawful and applications
services and devices well this rules
关于阻止流量，实际上有一个涉及 ISP 的案例
about blocking traffic and there
actually was a case involving an ISP
有阻止其客户使用 vonage 的做法，这是一种
that had a practice of blocking its
customers from using vonage which is a
与此竞争的 IP 语音服务是 p 自己的电话服务
voice over IP service that competed with
this is p's own telephone service that
不会被允许并注意该短语受合理网络限制
would not be allowed and notice the
phrase subject to reasonable network
当我们涵盖网络层控制时，管理将涵盖网络管理
management will cover network management
when we cover the network layer control
平面，但请注意，为了网络管理，允许阻塞流量
plane but note here that it is allowable
to block traffic for network management
目的是说如果网络降级，然后只有涓涓细流 量可以通过那么最好是网络管理流量能够
purposes say if the networks been
degraded and then only trickles of
目的是说如果网络降级，然后只有涓涓细流 量可以通过那么最好是网络管理流量能够
traffic can get through then it's best
that network management traffic be able
当然要解决什么是合理的网络管理的问题
to get through of course the question of
what reasonable network management is is
第二条明线规则有待解释
left open to interpretation
the second bright-line rule is no
作为 isp 引用取消引用的节流不应损害或降低合法性
throttling that is an isp quote unquote
shall not impair or degrade lawful
基于互联网内容的互联网效应 用或服务或使用无害设备再次受制于
Internet
effect on the basis of Internet content
基于互联网内容的互联网效应 用或服务或使用无害设备再次受制于
application or service or use of a non
harmful device again subject to
合理的网络管理注意这里的词受损或降级
reasonable network management note here
the words impaired or degrade there was
不久前一个 ISP 被判定干扰 BitTorrent 的案例
a case not too long ago where an ISP was
judged to be interfering with BitTorrent
点对点流量，它是通过内部创建和发送来实现的
peer-to-peer traffic and it was doing
this by internally creating and sending
TCP 重置数据包到 BitTorrent 客户端和在终端主机上执行的服务器
TCP reset packets to BitTorrent client
and servers executing at the end host
这导致主机基本上关闭了他们的 BitTorrent 连接 ISP
this caused the host to close their
BitTorrent connections basically the ISP
正在关闭 BitTorrent 应用程序下的 TCP 连接
was closing the TCP connection
underneath the BitTorrent application
它真的不想要谁的流量，然后最后是明线
whose traffic it really didn't want and
then finally there's the bright-line
无付费优先排序规则
rule of no paid prioritization
这意味着例如来自所有视频的视频流 媒体服务提供商必须被同等对待，例如
this means for example that video
streaming traffic from all video streaming service providers must be treated the same for
流媒体视频服务提供商无法付费以获得更好的数据包服务
example that one streaming video service provider cannot pay to get its packets better
他们的方式给客户，当然我们已经看到这是如何从一个
service on their way to the customer and of course we've seen how this
通过优先排队的技术观点你可能会问为什么没有付费
can be done from a technical point of view via priority queuing well you
优先排序，因为为优先服务付费似乎几乎就像
might ask why no paid prioritization since paying for a priority service seems well
至少在美国这里是生活的一个事实，也是争论的焦点之一
almost like a fact of life at least here in the United States well
是说如果说视频流服务提供商可以为更好的服务付费并且
one of the arguments is that if say a video streaming service provider can
如果那个成功的现任服务提供商可以支付很多费用
pay for better service and if that successful incumbent the existing service provider can
那么这会给新的竞争对手带来很高的进入壁垒，当然
pay a lot then this introduces a high barrier to entry for new competitors
一些国家想鼓励市场竞争，但也有反
and of course some countries want to encourage market competition but there are counter
对此的论点声称通过拥有为 ISP 创造额外收入
arguments to this claiming that creating additional revenues for an ISP by having paid
从竞争的角度来看，付费优先排序是一件好事，因为
prioritization is a good thing from a competitive point of view since that makes
使 ISP 市场更有利可图，因此更多的公司想要
the ISP marketplace more lucrative and so more companies will want to invest in
投资 ISP 市场或 ISP 将希望在他们的市场上投资更多
the ISP market or ISPs will want to invest more in their infrastructure and
基础设施，然后终于有法律可以追溯到近一百
then finally there are laws going back almost a hundred years that have regulated
将电话网络作为电信服务进行监管的年份
the telephone network as a telecommunications service provider but there's much less regulation of
提供者，但对信息服务的监管要少得多
ISP 那么什么是 ISP 是电信服务提供商还是
information service providers so what is an ISP is it a telecommunication service provider
从监管的角度来看，信息服务提供商很好
or an information service provider well it turns out from a regulatory standpoint the
这个问题的答案在美国很重要，但这个问题的答案
answer to this question matters a lot in the US but the answer to
问题真的还没有最终确定
this question has really not yet been finally determined well these bright-line rules are
好吧，这些明确的规则来自 2015 年美国 FCC 订单，最近 FCC
from a 2015 u.s. FCC order more recent FCC orders have actually rewritten much
订单实际上重写了 2015 年订单的大部分内容
所以直到法律成文，直到有进一步的诉讼和判例法
of that 2015 order so until laws are written and until there's further litigation
通过我认为简单地说情况继续发展是公平的
and case law adopted I think it's fair to simply say that the situation
我认为在许多国家都是如此 有趣的是我们已经
continues to evolve and I think that's true in many countries it's interesting that
有能力做优先级，因为互联网第一
we've had the ability to do prioritization since the internet first became public nearly
近 30 年前公开，所以虽然互联网有很强的
30 years ago so although the Internet has a strong technical foundation as we've
技术基础，正如我们在三十年后看到的我们的社会政治和
seen three decades later our social political and economic policies governing this creation that
管理这一创造的经济政策尚未完全
很好地定义或商定，结束了我们对数据包调度的讨论
have not yet been fully defined or agreed upon well that wraps up our
和数据包缓冲以及我希望是一个有趣的侧边栏
discussion of packet scheduling and packet buffering and also what I hope was an
网络中立的话题，更一般地说，它结束了我们对
interesting sidebar into the topic of network neutrality and more generally it wraps up
路由器内部是什么 记得我们还查看了输入端口 输出端口和
our discussion of what's inside a router remember we also looked at input ports
交换结构接下来我们要看看互联网
output ports and switching fabrics coming up next we're going to take a look
协议 ipv4 所以请继续关注 你[音乐]
at the Internet Protocol ipv4 so stay tuned for that
you  [Music]